Hello, in today's video we will
compare nb company's Yo 2.0. I
keep giving updates related to health and life insurance through this channel
and also give you advice on every insurance related
problem. Our
team has 12 years of experience in the insurance industry
and we
also provide consultancy related to claims. Let's
start today's video. First of all, we will talk
about the special features of these plans
which make them the best plans.
In Yo 2.0 plan, you get Booster Plus
benefit, in which the sum inshot which you do
not use is carried forward to the next year
and it
goes up to a maximum of 10x. The second special thing in the Niva Bupa
plan is that here you get the
lock the clock benefit, in which your
premium gets locked at the same age at which
you take the policy. You will pay the same premium in this plan
until you make a claim from the policy.
You keep paying the premium according to that age
in this plan. The third special thing
in the Niva Bupa plan is that here
you get a disease management rider.
If your BP and diabetes pre-
existing
rider is not available to you, let us
tell you about the
special features of the next plan, i.e. ADAC Optima Secure Plan.
Here you get Secure
Benefit, in which you get 2x coverage
from day one. Secondly, you get Plus Benefit in this plan, in
which whether you make a claim or
not, your policy will increase 1x in 2 years
because you will get loyalty benefit.
Next, global coverage
is also available in this plan, that is, if someone wants global cover in
which your worldwide treatment can be
covered, then you can take this plan.
Now let us know about the
special features of ICICI Lord's Health Advantage Plan. The
cumulative bonus you get in this plan does
not reduce every year. The
second benefit of this plan is that
if you take a policy with a sub-insurance of Rs 25 lakh, then
you
get inbuilt global coverage in the plan, which allows
you to get treatment outside India as well.
Third benefit: If you want maternity coverage
in your policy, then you can
add a rider for it.  You can do this so that
after nine months your maternity
expenses and newborn baby
expenses will be covered in this plan. So we
talked about the unique features of these plans.
Now we will know
which variants are available to you in these plans
and what is the entry age in these plans.
Five variants are available in Niva Bap Resh 2.0 plan which
are Bronze,
Gold, Bronze Plus, Platinum Plus and
Titanium Plus. Talking about the entry age, the
adult age in this plan is 18 to 65
years and the child age is from 91 days to 30
years. Talking about the entry age in this plan, the
child age is from 91 days to 25
years. Now talking about the ICICI Lombard
plan, only one variant is available in this plan which
is Apex Plus.
Talking about the entry age, the adult
age in this plan is from 18 to 65 years and the child
age is from 91 days to 25 years.  Years have been defined.
Now let's talk about room rent eligibility. There is
no restriction on room rent in all the three plans. Let's talk about the
sum assured of all the three plans. How much
sum assured can you choose in these plans? In the RISH 2.0 plan, the minimum sum assured is 5 lakhs
and the maximum is 1 crore. In the Optimal Secure
plan, the minimum sum assured is 5 lakhs and the
maximum is 2 crores. In ICICI Lombard
's Health Advantage plan, the minimum sum
assured is 5 lakhs and the maximum is 3 crores.
Now let's talk about the bonuses available in these plans.
In the RISHOT plan,
you have Booster Plus benefit available, which means
whatever sum assured you are not using
this year will be carried forward to the next year
and the maximum will be carried forward up to 10x.
In the ADAC Optima Secure plan,
you get Plus benefit in which you
get a bonus addition of 50%.  The
plan
offers a no-claim bonus of 20%, which goes up to a maximum of 100%
and is not reduced in case of a claim.
You will get this guaranteed no-claim bonus here. Next, all three
plans cover day care
treatments, AYUSH hospitalization, and domicile
treatments. All plans cover up
to this limit. Next, you get a
refill benefit under these plans,
also known as restore and recharge benefit.
In the Niva Bappa Rasher plan,
you get a refill benefit in which, if
your bed sum insured is exhausted, the company will
refill your sum insured again. This benefit will be provided
unlimited times in this plan
as long as you have the policy.
You can use it for any illness.
Now, in the HDFC plan,
once-a-year refill benefit
is available. Unlimited restore rider is available to you,
which you
can add to the policy by paying an extra premium. Next,
in IIIrd's Health Advantage plan, once-
in-a-year refill benefit is provided.  You get refill benefit
which you can use for any illness.
Now let us know up to
what extent you are covered for emergency road ambulance. In the Niva B
Reya 2.0 plan, you have ambulance cover.
Age per actuals up to the sum assured are covered.
In the ADFC Optima Secure plan also,
you have age per actuals up to the sum assured cover.
In the ICICI Lombard plan, you have
road ambulance cover up to minimum road ambulance expenses of up to 1 per of the sum assured per hospitalization and maximum up to 10,000 per hospitalization.
Along with road ambulance,
you will also get emergency air ambulance cover.
In the Niva B plan, you have
air ambulance cover up to 2 lakhs.
In the ADFC Optima Secure plan, you will be covered up to 5 lakhs.
In the ICICI Lombard plan, you have air ambulance cover up to the sum assured.
Compliance is included in the Reya 2.0
plan. You get wellness tests once a year,
which you can avail on a cashless basis.  If the
sum assured is Rs 10 lakh,
you can get tests done up to Rs 5,000.
In a policy of Rs 20 lakh, you can get tests done up to Rs 10,000.
Now, in the HDFC Optiemus Secure
plan, you get tests done on renewal,
which you
can also avail on a cashless as well as reimbursement basis. In a Rs 10 lakh
plan, you can avail tests up to Rs 5,000.
In a Rs 15 lakh policy, you
can avail tests up to Rs 8,000. In policies of Rs 20, 25 and 50
lakh, you can avail tests up to Rs 10,000.
In a policy with a sum assured of Rs 1 to 2 crore, you can get tests done up to Rs 15,000.
In the ICICI Lombard Health Advantage plan, you can get tests done on an annual basis, up to a maximum of Rs
10,000
on a cashless basis. Now, let's talk
about the wellness benefit, which
is available only in the Nema V Reshot plan.  30
but is not available in the other two plans.
Pre and post hospitalization
expenses will be covered in all three plans, in
which pre-hospitalization is covered for
60 days and post-hospitalization is
covered for 180 days.
You get e-consultation benefit in RISH 2.2 plan.
You get the facility of unlimited consultation and second medical opinion
once a year. In ADFC Optima plan,
you can take doctor consultations on 51 listed critical analyses
and
you also get e-consultation facility in ICICI Lombard plan.
Modern
treatments and robotic surgeries will be
covered up to the sum in short
in all three plans, but
you will face a limit on robotic surgery in RISH plan. Now let's talk
about payment and deductible for OPD coverage.
You will get OPD cover in RISH 2.0 plan, in which you will get OPD cover.
On taking acute care rider, up to Rs. 200,000 per person.
Optima Well Being in ADFC  You will get
OPD cover in the rider. In the ICICI plan,
you will get OPD cover under the B Fit rider. Let us
know about the copayment, then
you do not have to pay any copayment in all the three plans.
Deductible is available to you in
RISH 2.0
and Optima Secure plan and in other
Health Advantage plans, deductible is
not available to you. Talking about global cover,
you do not get global cover in the RISH 2.0 plan
and
you have global cover available in HDFC and ICICI Lord.
Maternity expenses are not covered in Niva Bupa and HDFC.
In ICICI Lord, you can take Age and Add-on maternity coverage,
which will cover your
delivery expenses, newborn baby and
vaccination expenses. Now,
you get some optional riders in these plans,
which you can avail by paying an additional premium. Let us
know about them. In RISH B,
you get Safeguard Acute Care OPD
Rider, Hospital Cash Benefits Safeguard.
Plus Rider and PA Rider options
are available on
hdfcergo.com. Sum Insurance Protector
is also available. Apart from this, you get
maternity benefits which will cover your three
deliveries. You also
get personal accident cover here.
After all this, one important thing is that you should know
that the more riders you add to your policy, the more
your premium will
increase. Therefore, you should add only those riders to
your policy which you
actually need. Let's talk
about the waiting period of these plans. The
initial waiting period in all three plans
is 30 days. For specific illnesses,
you will have a waiting period of 2 years.
In ICI Lombard, you will have a waiting period of 3 years.
We will keep bringing
important information related to health and life insurance for you. All those who are
associated with us, please continue with us
in this journey. And if you are new to our channel, then
please subscribe to our channel
and our